# **KEENAN JONES**

Willing to Relocate | 312-757-9548 | keenanjones210@gmail.com <u>Github | Medium | Linkedin</u>

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React Redux. I spent six years as a massage therapist both as an employee and business owner. Looking to make a career change, I discovered web development. The enjoyment of coding and the creative outlet it provides made it clear this was the path for me. Possessing strong skills in problem-solving, customer service and communication, I'm able to convey complex issues to both technical and non-technical audiences. Highly energized by teamwork and collaboration.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Git, Ruby on Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Node, Active Record, Sinatra, Redux, MongoDB, NoSQL, Postman, Gatsbyjs, Expressjs, Strapi, and Contentful.

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# ShoutRandomly - Github | Demo

A social media app; follow other users, create posts and edit profiles.

- Integration of image uploading with Active storage.
- Linked Material UI with React for simple client interface.
- Assembled RESTful design of database to organize information from server to client.

### Day21 - Github | Demo

An app that is a twist on an to-do list.

- Produced API functionality with Ruby on Rails MVC pattern for data storage, simple requests and using Serializers.
- Implemented user interface employing React and Redux with Material UI for styling.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.

### Weather App Widget - Github | Demo

A weather display app; search based on zip code or city.

- Capitalized on React's lifecycle methods to conditionally render components.
- Utilized openweathermap API to pull and parse data on weather from across the globe.
- Managed font, images and palette with Material UI withStyles for design flexibility.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Owner, Oasis Theory, Chicago, IL

4/2014 - Present

- Assessed client's issues and created health routines for clients to become healthier.
- Collaborated with clients to help them accomplish their goals.
- Researched client's physical issues with external healthcare professionals to educate clients.

### Massage Therapist, Evolution Spine and Sport, Evanston, IL

5/2018 - 11/2019

- Communicated with internal and external healthcare professionals to improve client's current health routine.
- Assisted with the marketing strategy for the Massage Department.
- Executed the massage portion of the client's health regimen.

# **EDUCATION**

### Flatiron School, Chicago, IL

1/2020 - 4/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript immersive program

### Oakton Community College, Skokie, IL

1//2015 - 12/2015

Coursework completed towards an Associate's Degree in Biology

# Atlanta School of Massage Therapy, Atlanta, GA

11/2013 - 06/2014

Neuromuscular Therapy Certification Sport Therapies Certification

Deep Tissue Certification